Isaiah Richards

Houghton, MI 49931 (561) 597-0101 isaiahbenrichards@gmail.com github.com/isaiahbenrichards

SUMMARY

Driven, aspiring, Cybersecurity Professional. Seeking a position as a SOC analyst. Highly skilled at explaining technical details at a high level and working with people. International travel experience in over 10 countries. 15+ years experience in sales and management.

CompTIA Security+ certified. Solid, fundamental knowledge of offensive and defensive security, AWS, Azure, and GCP, SIEM tools, vulnerability management, Windows, Linux, Powershell, Python and SQL.

HANDS-ON LAB EXPERIENCE

Junior Penetration Tester— Try Hack Me July 2024

Network Security - Learned basic principles of passive and active reconnaissance, common protocols and attack vectors.

Vulnerability Research - Basic familiarity and hands-on experience with the skills, research methods, and resources used to exploit vulnerable applications and systems.

SOC Level 1 — Try Hack Me March 2024 - April 2024

Cyber Threat Intelligence - Learned about identifying and using available security knowledge to mitigate and manage potential adversary actions.

Network Security and Traffic Analysis – Understand the core concepts of Network Security and Traffic Analysis to spot and probe network anomalies using industry tools and techniques with a strong emphasis on IDS/IPS and Wireshark.

Security Information and Event Management - Understand how SIEM works and comfortable creating simple and advanced search queries to look for specific answers from the ingested logs.

Phishing - Learned how to analyze and defend against phishing emails. Investigated real-world phishing attempts using a variety of techniques.

Cyber Defense — Try Hack Me March 2024 - April 2024

Threat and Vulnerability Management – Identify how attackers are developing their techniques to use in your defensive strategy.

Malware Analysis - Analyze malicious files to prevent malicious actions and identify attacks.

SKILLS

Splunk

Burp Suite

Metasploit

Nmap

Wireshark

Try Hack Me Top 1%

Analytical Thinking

Ability to Work in a Team

Interpersonal Communication Skills

Risk Management

Vulnerability Management

Cloud Computing

MITRE ATT&CK Framework

CERTIFICATES

CompTIA Security+

Qualys Certified Specialist

Google Cybersecurity

Google IT Support

CompTIA Network+ (currently
studying)

AWS Solutions Architect (currently studying)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Calumet Electronics Corp., Calumet,MI — Layup Technician

February 2023 - Present

Skilled Layup Technician proficient in assembling and fabricating circuit boards with precision and attention to detail. Experienced in following technical specifications and blueprints to ensure optimal performance and reliability. Capable of operating machinery and equipment to meet production deadlines while maintaining quality standards.

Curated.com — *Coffee Expert*

June 2023 - Present

Engaging with and providing product recommendations to prospective customers. Supporting content creation needs, such as authoring articles, compiling topmost recommended product lists, generating Q & A content, etc. Validating marketing approach.

Sugar Dragon LLC, Houghton, MI — Head Coffee Roaster

July 2021 - Present

All coffee roasting and profile development. Acquisition & management of wholesale accounts. Selection & purchase of all green coffees.

EDUCATION

Michigan Technological Univ., Houghton, MI — Finance